### R. Rajagurulingam = "Raja"

Block 919, Jurong West Street 91, #10-122, Singapore 640919 Contact No: +65 9240 0142; Email id: <a href="mailto:rrajaguru.sj@gmail.com">rrajaguru.sj@gmail.com</a> Current Status: Singapore Permanent Resident, since 2008.

#### About me

Globally experienced, detail orientated proactive business leader with deep experience spanning technical, operation, business development, showing strong organizational awareness in a technically challenging industry with an MBA, and a strong record of accomplishment of driving and accelerating profitable growth, transforming inefficient and unprofitable customers and businesses, and strengthening team engagement.

With strong resilience, high tolerance for ambiguity and strong emotional, cultural intelligence with the ability to self-reflect and moderate my style in response to the needs of the environment culminates together to drive a strong strategic mindset, managing complexity, driving changes, developing talent to create, capture and sustain business value over both the short and long term.

#### **Career Objective**

To succeed in an atmosphere of growth and excellence and make a career which gives me satisfaction and self-development and helps me achieve the goals of the company.

#### **Education**

- G7 Expert Certificate, Year 2021 Idealliance, USA
- Lean Six Sigma Black Belt, Year 2015
  Neville-Clarke, Singapore
- MBA: Year 2014
  Anamalai University, India
- Bachelor of Chemistry, Year 2001
  Manonmaniam Sundaranar University, India

#### **Experience**

Work History: Siegwerk Pte Ltd, Singapore.

<u>Head of Process Management & Consulting Services, SEA North (2016 to present **Siegwerk** Pte Ltd, Singapore.</u>

# Roles & Responsibilities

- My main work consists to ensure the support to Business units and customers with cost reduction/efficiency consulting activities and projects of ink management and printing processes in consideration of performance, cost and business strategy. Functionally reporting to Head of Global Process Management & Consulting Manager, Germany. Managed and coached two direct reports
- Optimizing the processes in the print shop. Advice and support along the whole of the added value chain from the prepress stage to further processing.
- In conjunction with, analyze and optimize the printing production processes, identify possible savings, propose actions and help to implement them.

- The objective is to increase transparency with customer and improve productivity, thus contributing to sustained business development
- Cooperation and synergy with *technology*, and SCM and to realize and agree defined projects and objectives
- Established ink formulation and color qc process across global customer at SEA
- Analysis and observation of markets and competitors as well as analysis of technology and logistic based innovations within the *printing industry*
- Advice and consult internal counterparts/BU's within the framework of business support
- Negotiate and deal with external partner and customer
- Development and implementation of technology requirements of efficient system and procedures.
- Implementation and realization of Onsite consulting activities according to the business plan and global strategy, set objective and execute corrective actions in case of deviations; *implementation and realization* of Siegwerk onsite consulting strategy.
- Implementation and realization of Siegwerk harmonized ink room concept. Set objectives to ink room accordingly, execute corrective actions in case of deviations in the region.
- Drive of ink room practices @ region and development efficient ink room system and procedure.
- Audit and evaluate service and operations provided by Siegwerk and drive improvements

### **Achievements:**

- Successfully managed to do audit and saving potential flexible label customer in Hanoi -€0.53m
- Process optimization savings in Global Flexible printing in Thailand -€0.2m
- Successfully managed the press optimization project in Label customer in Thailand -€0.19m

#### **Professional Experience Achievements**

Work History: Siegwerk Pte Ltd, Singapore.

Application Technical Manager (2013 to 2016) Siegwerk Pte Ltd, Singapore.

#### Responsibilities

Reporting to Regional Technology Manager. As an Application Technologist I was responsible for developing products for water base *flexo* printing technology and assessing market needs.

- Worked cross functionally I have defined and created various tools, reports to align and share our **know-how** in the organization.
- I was a key contributor and part of **global technology team** for market strategy/ product development.
- Development of innovative technology applications, service and solution according to customer requirements in line with defined objectives, quality standards and budgets
- Cooperation with water based technology, GIN and Analytical laboratory in the development of identified technology solutions to ensure they comply with customer and market needs
- Continuous Market and competitor analysis from the technology point of view to ensure the development of competitive application, service and solutions to respond market and customer needs
- Efficient project management to provide defined technology solutions, application and services according to agreed timeliness, budgets and standards
- Accurate and comprehensive documentation and reporting on technology portfolio developments and progress in line with defined standards.
- In cooperation with technology, sale and SCM *leverage new business*, realize and agree defined projects and objectives
- People and skill development in the global technical organization. Training and hands on support to technology

- Implementation and realization of Siegwerk *harmonized Technical Concept*, set objective to Technology team accordingly, execute corrective actions in case of deviations in the region
- Technical Support to Global Flexible & Label customers.
- Where applicable, lead and motivate staff to improve performance and continuously develop professional expertise.
- Deliver Quality disciplines to Customer Quality milestones and requirements
- Streamline Quality processes and develop "Quality Excellence" mindset

### **Achievements:**

- Optimized the water based product according to customer needs
- Improved morale and team work in QA team
- Reduction of Customer defects and secure the business.
- Set up a KPI driven scorecard system improved visibility of concerns from all functional areas and their effect on Company level scorecard

Assistant In plant Manager (2008 to 2012) Siegwerk Pte Ltd, Singapore.= Customer Service Manager

### Responsibilities

- Coordinate with customer(Tetra Pak Singapore) to trouble shoot their technical challenges related to ink
- Promotes positive customer relations and displays professionalism
- Standardization of the manufacturing processes and the implementation of standard operating procedure
- A focus on waste reduction and ink mileage
- Works closely with Area Technical Manager to assure proper procedures, work flow, quality and customer relations standards are meet.
- Testing of new and existing products from laboratory and manufacture
- Ensure good 5S are practiced on the line
- · Technical Support to international customer
- Providing INK MAKER SOFTWARE training to the technicians
- Coordinate the launch of minor and major launches in plants
- Delivery of "business critical" Six Sigma /lean Project savage the production of daily schedule

### **Achievements:**

- Technically confident and able to converse with customers, suppliers and technical contact in detail about water based ink
- · Recognized for leading the integration in daily operational problem solving
- Managed and safe implementation of significant changes in production through kickoff with
  5S activities
- Elimination of Failure mode (Excessive noise) in Technical/Customer Satisfaction
- Achieved "Best Employee" Award

# In Plant Technician (2006 to 2007) Siegwerk Pte Ltd, Singapore.

#### Responsibilities

- Weigh, blend, QC and deliver in a productive, efficient and safe manner press ready ink to meet the demands of the customer's production schedule
- Follow appropriate quality control an inspection process for inks to ensure quality to presses
- Assist with job scheduling an ink estimations for jobs going to press
- · Assist with maintaining the work off ink process by regulating use and storage
- Review suitability of press returns ink for recycle
- Validation of ink color matches to ensure customer specifications
- Lead & Manage the team members (3)

#### **Achievements:**

- Good People Management
- Multi task handling
  - Color matching, Quality Control, Inventory Control & Press Support
  - o Team Management

**Technical Supervisor**: Sicpa Pte Ltd, India (From 2002 to 2005)

### **Achievements**

- To provide technical support for *ITC* (offset, flexo & gravure products)
- Lead and participate in improvement projects to improve equipment uptime, yield and reduce cost
- Offset, Flexo Ink color matching according to the customer sample
- Problem Solving

# **Skills and Certificate**

- Essentials for print & Media Industry, Singapore 2008
- Apply Quality System , Singapore, 2010
- Certified in operation specialist, Singapore, 2010
- Heart & art of people management, NUS, Singapore, 2010
- Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, Singapore 2011
- Lean Six Sigma Black Belt, Singapore, 2015
- Repro to print, Janoschka, Malaysia, 2015
- Xceed, Siegwerk Lean management, Germany 2015
- Global leadership training, Malaysia 2019
- Strategic Value Selling , Thailand 2019
- Color Management Professional, Idealliance 2021
- G7 Expert Certificate, Idealliance 2021

#### Other Details

- Languages Known: English & Tamil.
- Nationality: Indian.
- Current Status: Singapore Permanent Resident, since 2008